Front End Developer

Serhii Kushnir

Poland

+48 577 264 738

s1983kushnir@.gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/serhiikushnir/

GitHub

As a front-end developer with strong technical experience in team projects, I reduced token usage in OpenAI API prompts, cutting costs by 20%. My attention to detail ensures adherence to technical requirements and pixel-perfect UIs. With an engineering background in teamwork and problem-solving, I aim to bring my skills to a new company for mutual success.

CAREER EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer Junfolio

September 2024 - Present

MarketPlace | GitHub [Next.is, TS, Tailwind CSS, Redux]

Application Development: A platform that connects startups with collaborators to combine talent and expertise

Collaboration & Optimization: Refactored code, images with SVG sprites to reduce HTTP requests, improving page load times and application efficiency.

Components: User profile, forms, using library React-Hook-Form.

Full Stack Developer Reel-Reveal

January 2024 - Present

Reel-Reveal | GitHub [Next.js, React TS, Tailwind CSS, OpenAl API, MongoDB, TMDB]

Application Development: Contributed to building a responsive web app for movie discovery, using TMDB API and OpenAI API.

Collaboration & Optimization: Worked with a UX designer to create a user-friendly and pixel-perfect interface. I optimized the API integration, cutting token usage and costs by 20%.

MongoDB Integration: Set up MongoDB for efficient data storage.

Personalized Recommendations: Implemented an interactive quiz that utilizes the OpenAI API to generate tailored movie suggestions for users.

Senior Design Engineer Vericom

2013 - 2024, Kyiv, Ukraine

Designed, debugged, and managed the full production cycle of LED lighting devices. Constructed CNC machine tools for production use. Oversaw customer consultations and managed the entire production process.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML, CSS
- React
- SASS, Styled
 Components, Tailwind
- · Responsive design
- · Git
- · Node.js
- MongoDB

EDUCATION

GOIT

Full Stack Development

2022 - 2023

<u>Certificate</u>

NATIONAL AVIATION UNIVERSITY

MSc in Energy Engineering

LANGUAGES

Ukrainian - native Rassian - native English - B1

PROJECTS

<u>GoosTrack</u> | <u>GitHub</u> [React, RTK Query, Node.js, Styled Component, Recharts]

Group project. Schedule planning app. Role: statistics page.

Filmoteka | GitHub [HTML, JS, SASS, Parcel, TUI pagination]

Individual project. An application for creating your own movie library.

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process in accordance with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 (General Data Protection Regulation) I also consent to the processing of my personal data for future recruitment processes.